const QuizData = [
  {
    id: 0,
    question: ` What is the Capital Of India ?`,
    options: [`New Delhi`, `Mumbai`, `Kolkatta`],
    answer: `New Delhi`
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    question: `Who is the CEO of Tesla Motors?`,
    options: [`Bill Gates`, `Steve Jobs`, `Elon Musk`],
    answer: `Elon Musk`
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: `Name World's Richest Man?`,
    options: [`Jeff Bezo`, `Bill Gates`, `Mark Zuckerberg`],
    answer: `Jeff Bezo`
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: `World's Longest River?`,
    options: [`River Nile`, `River Amazon`, `River Godavari`],
    answer: `River Nile`
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: ` Which is the latitude that runs through the centre of the Earth?`,
    options: [`Tropics of Cancer`, `Capricorn`, `Arctic`, `equator`],
    answer: `Equator`
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: `  Which is the tallest mountain in the world?`,
    options: [`K2`, `Mount Everest`, `Kanchenjunga`, `Lhotse`],
    answer: `Mount Everest`
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: `Which is the biggest oceans of the world?`,
    options: [`Indian`, `Southern`, `Pacific`, `Arctic`, `Atlantic`],
    answer: `Pacific`
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Which country has the highest population?`,
    options: [`United States`, `China`, `India`, `Indonesia`],
    answer: `China`
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: ` Which is the largest waterfall in the world?`,
    options: [`Niagara Falls`, `Victoria Falls`, `Angel Falls`, `Iguazu Falls`],
    answer: ` Victoria Falls`
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: `Which is the largest desert in the world?`,
    options: [
      `Sahara Desert`,
      `Syrian Desert `,
      `Great Basin Desert`,
      `Arabian Desert `
    ],
    answer: `Sahara Desert`
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: `Branches of a river are called Tributaries?`,
    options: [`true`, `false`],
    answer: `true`
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: ` Which is the largest island in the world?`,
    options: [`New Guinea`, `Greenland`, `Borneo`],
    answer: `Greenland`
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: `Magma does not heats the water in a hot spring.`,
    options: [`true`, `false`],
    answer: `false`
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: `Which is the coldest continent in the world? `,
    options: [`Africa`, `Antarctica `, `North-America`, `Europe`],
    answer: ` Antarctica`
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: `Which is the world’s smallest country? `,
    options: [` Monaco`, `Nauru `, `San Marino`, `Vatican City`],
    answer: `Vatican City `
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: `Where is the Tower Bridge located? `,
    options: [`London,UK`, `NewYork,US`, `Mumbai,India`, `Beijing,China`],
    answer: `London, UK `
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: `Where is the Leaning Tower of Pisa located? `,
    options: [`London,UK `, `Delhi,India `, `Pisa,Italy`, `Paris,France`],
    answer: ` Pisa, Italy `
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: `How many countries are present in Africa? `,
    options: [`46 countries`, `54 countries`, `67 countries`, `43 countries`],
    answer: `54 countries `
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: `Which planet is closest to Planet Earth? `,
    options: [`Venus`, `Mars`, `Juspiter`, `Saturn`],
    answer: ` Venus`
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: ` What is the currency in Cambodia?`,
    options: [`Euro `, `USD`, `Yen`, `Riel `],
    answer: `Riel `
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: `How do you measure the speed of wind?`,
    options: [`Protractor`, `Hygrometer `, `Anemometer`, `Thermometer`],
    answer: `Anemometer `
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: `Name the river that is not crossed by any bridges. `,
    options: [`Nile`, `Amazon `, `Yangtze`, `,Mississippi`],
    answer: `Amazon `
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question: `Name the city that is located in two countries. `,
    options: [`Istanbul`, `Charleroi`, `Damascus`, `Calgary`],
    answer: `Istanbul `
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: `Which line separates Indian and China? `,
    options: [
      `Durand Line`,
      `McMahon Line`,
      `Maginot Line `,
      `Mac-Mahon line `
    ],
    answer: `Mac-Mahon line `
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: `Where is Acropolis situated? `,
    options: [
      `Paris, France`,
      `Athens, Greece `,
      `Mannila, Philippines`,
      `Isfahan, Iran `
    ],
    answer: `Athens, Greece `
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: `Which country produces maximum aluminium in the world? `,
    options: [`Iran`, `Philippines `, `Jamaica`, `India`],
    answer: `Jamaica `
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: `Where can you find the ‘Desert of Death’? `,
    options: [`Thar Desert`, `Gobi Desert`, `Dasht-e Margo`, `Sahara Desert`],
    answer: `Dasht-e Margo`
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: `What type of deserts are Gobi desert and Atacama desert? `,
    options: [
      `Rainshadow deserts`,
      `Subtropical deserts`,
      `Coastal deserts`,
      `Polar deserts`
    ],
    answer: ` Rainshadow deserts`
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: `On which day of the year is the Sun closest to the Earth? `,
    options: [`May 27th `, `January 4th `, `December 22nd`, `June 21st`],
    answer: `January 4th `
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: `What is the highest active volcano in Europe? `,
    options: [`Vesuvius`, `Yellowstone`, `Taal `, `Mount Etna `],
    answer: `Mount Etna `
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: `The Buran wind blows across: `,
    options: [
      `Eastern Asia `,
      `Eastern Australia`,
      `Southern Africa`,
      `Western Europe `
    ],
    answer: `Eastern Asia `
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: `Which of the following countries does not share its border with Black Sea? `,
    options: [`Georgia`, `Turkey`, ` Bulgaria`, `  Belarus`],
    answer: `Belarus `
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question: `Which of the following is not an example of systematic approach of geography? `,
    options: [
      `Physical geography`,
      `Human geography`,
      `Regional geography `,
      ` Environmental geography `
    ],
    answer: `Regional geography `
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: `Next to sun, which is the nearest star of the earth? `,
    options: [`Apha centuari `, `Orion`, `Usra Major`, `Sirius `],
    answer: `Apha centuari `
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: `Which of the following countries is not larger than India in terms of geographical area?`,
    options: [`Australia`, `Brazil `, `Canada`, `Indonesia`],
    answer: `Indonesia `
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: `Which of the following is an example of direct source to study interior of the earth?  `,
    options: [
      `Gravitation`,
      `Volcanic Eruption `,
      ` Magnetic field`,
      ` Sesimic activity `
    ],
    answer: `Volcanic Eruption `
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question: `Which of the following rocks are known as Primary rocks? `,
    options: [
      `Sedimentary Rocks`,
      `Metamorphic Rocks `,
      `Igneous Rocks `,
      `None of the above`
    ],
    answer: ` `
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: `Which among the following country has the largest share in global mangrove areas? `,
    options: [`Brazil`, `Mexico`, `Indonesia `, `Australia `],
    answer: `Indonesia `
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: `Littoral forests are rich sources of which among the following? `,
    options: [`Firewood`, `Timber`, `Fodder `, `Bamboo `],
    answer: `Firewood `
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: `Which among the following starts represent the Morning and Evening Stars? `,
    options: [
      `Mercury, Venus`,
      `Venus, Mercury`,
      `Mercury, Mercury`,
      `Venus, Venus`
    ],
    answer: `Venus, Venus `
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    question: `Which of the following is the largest of the seven member states of United Arab Emirates? `,
    options: [`Abu Dhabi `, `Ras al-Khaimah`, `Sharjah`, ``],
    answer: `Abu Dhabi `
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    question: `Apart from Saturn which of the following possess planetary possess ring systems of their own? `,
    options: [
      `Jupiter only`,
      `Jupiter, Uranus & Neptune`,
      `Jupiter & Uranus `,
      `Jupiter & Neptune `
    ],
    answer: `Jupiter, Uranus & Neptune `
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    question: `What is approximate diameter of Milky Way? `,
    options: [
      `100000 light years `,
      `10000 light years `,
      `1000 light years`,
      ` 1000000 Light Years`
    ],
    answer: ` 100000 light years`
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    question: `Chomolungma is located in which country? `,
    options: [`India`, `Bhutan`, `Tibet `, `  Nepal`],
    answer: ` Nepal `
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    question: `On which of the following dates Autumnal Equinox occurs? `,
    options: [`March 21`, `June 21`, ` September 23 `, `March 21 `],
    answer: ` September 23 `
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    question: `In India when there is summer season, what is the season in Chile? `,
    options: [`Summer`, `Spring`, `Winter `, `Autumn `],
    answer: `Winter `
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    question: `Which among the following is not among the ancient list of seven wonders of world? `,
    options: [
      `Statue of Zeus at Olympia `,
      `Great Wall of China`,
      `Colossus of Rhodes `,
      `Tajmahal`
    ],
    answer: ` `
  },
  {
    id: 48,
    question: `Nickel & Iron are the main constituents of __________? `,
    options: [`Earth Core `, `Earth Crust`, `Mantle`, `None of the above `],
    answer: `Earth Core `
  },
  {
    id: 49,
    question: `While going towards the centre of the earth, the weight of a body shall ? `,
    options: [`Increase `, `Decrease `, `Remain Constant`, `Become infinite`],
    answer: `Decrease `
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    question: `The International Space Station is located in which among the following orbits? `,
    options: [
      `Low Earth Orbit (LEO) `,
      `Medium Earth orbit (MEO) `,
      `Intermediate Circular Orbit (ICO)`,
      `Geostationary Orbit (GEO)`
    ],
    answer: `Low Earth Orbit (LEO) `
  }
];

export default QuizData;
